<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Exploration on Kevin Davenport Engineering &amp; ML blog</title>
    <link>https://kldavenport.com/tags/data-exploration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Exploration on Kevin Davenport Engineering &amp; ML blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 11:54:26 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kldavenport.com/tags/data-exploration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wild Aataset Has Appeared! Now What?</title>
      <link>https://kldavenport.com/a-wild-dataset-has-appeared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 11:54:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kldavenport.com/a-wild-dataset-has-appeared/</guid>
      <description>Where do we start when we stumble across a dataset we don’t know much about? Lets say one where we don’t necessarily understand the underlying generative process for some or all of the variables. Lets assume for now we’re sure there aren’t one off interventions or level shifts in the data, and we don’t know anything about the distribution of the features, trends, seasonality, model parameters, variance, etc.
I tend to start with the simplest, most interpretable models first, regardless if the problem requires classification, regression, or causality modeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lending Club Data Analysis with Python</title>
      <link>https://kldavenport.com/lending-club-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 11:54:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kldavenport.com/lending-club-python/</guid>
      <description>Lending Club is the first peer-to-peer lending company to register its offerings as securities with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). Their operational statistics are public and available for download. It has been a while since I’ve posted an end to end solution blog post and would like to replicate the post with a bit more sophistication in Python with the latest dataset from lendinglub.com. In summary, let’s examine all the attributes Lending Club collects on users and how they influence the interest rates issued.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>