<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Davenport Engineering &amp; ML blog</title>
    <link>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kevin Davenport Engineering &amp; ML blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchorage, Alaska</title>
      <link>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/anchorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/anchorage/</guid>
      <description>We were in Anchorage for a conference and did not miss the opportunity to explore local trails. We also had time to sneak in an easy hike with a huge payoff: Flattop Mountain. Whenever I visit a new city, I work to find a community of like minded folks that can plug me into the community. I ventured out to AMH a fantastic mountaineering shop with a selection of rare pro-gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oaxaca, Mexico</title>
      <link>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/oaxaca/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/oaxaca/</guid>
      <description>About 80 of us from around the world headed east to the Oaxacan “Sierra Norte” located about 1.5 hours from Oaxaca city for the Transierra Norte. My photos do not do this beautiful state justice so take a look at pictures of last year&amp;rsquo;s event.
Diego snaped me going down what I think was a stage on day 3.
The trails were so spectacularly long and started at such a high altitude (+10k ft), that we&amp;rsquo;d see many distinct ecosystems and terrain over the course of one stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss, Italian, and French Alps</title>
      <link>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/aosta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/aosta/</guid>
      <description>I just got back from Fluidride&amp;rsquo;s 2018 Alps trip where we rode the Swiss Italian, and French alps. Coming from the PNW I always find myself comparing destination trails to what I have in my backyard back home. You want awkward and rowdy: North Shore, Long shuttle-able diverse downhill: Tres Hombres, Legit freeride and fortitude challenging rock rolls: Squamish, skill park progression for all levels 30min from Seattle: Duthie Hill. The list goes on and on, the PNW has it all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whistler, British Columbia</title>
      <link>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/whistler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/whistler/</guid>
      <description>This shot of Christian on In Deep&amp;nbsp;captures the relentless tech of what is probably the hardest double-black technical trail on Whistler.
Whistler is at the end of&amp;nbsp; a long steep windy road (BC-99) along the beautiful Howe Sound.&amp;nbsp; The drive makes you wonder how drivers navigate it safely in the snow. We rode about 80% of the trails offered over our 3 day stay in Creekside. If you care to avoid the commercial hustle and bustle of the main village, I highly recommend staying at Creekside, which offers non-congested lift access and a compliment of its own great trails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mérida, Yucatán</title>
      <link>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/merida/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kldavenport.com/bike-travel/merida/</guid>
      <description>Monumento a la Patria at the End of Paseo Montejo
Merida is a beautiful unique city with the styling and diversity that an average American tourist would expect out of cities in western Europe. One of my most memorable experiences during my weeks bushwhacking in the Yucatan was cruising along the beautiful wide tree-lined streets of Paseo de Montejo during the Sunday Bici-Ruta. The city closes a series of streets to all automobile traffic every Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>